[{"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba9b", "question": "What chapel do Cardinals congregate in to elect a new Pope?", "answer": "Sistine Chapel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a66", "question": "The Broadway musical \"Man of La Mancha\" was based on which novel?", "answer": "Don Quixote", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c06", "question": "What year was Marvin Gaye shot and killed by his father?", "answer": "1984", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5901d9e6709c1c34536e6ead", "question": "The fans of Taylor Swift are known as what?", "answer": "Swifties", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388da", "question": "Who was the Greek goddess of marriage and women as well as the queen of heaven?", "answer": "Hera", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133caae", "question": "What do zoologists call the leader of a wolf pack?", "answer": "The alpha male", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339934", "question": "What US city is mentioned in the first line of the Bob Seger song \"Turn the Page\"?", "answer": "Omaha", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6010cad70775fa611bce67ff", "question": "The ancient Chinese concept of harmonious design, which is a balance between humans and their environment, is called what?", "answer": "Feng Shui", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abf3", "question": "What major city lies on the River Torrens?", "answer": "Adelaide", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b9e", "question": "What classical composer was the subject of a #1 hit song in 1986 by Falco?", "answer": "Mozart", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1cd", "question": "What did Pieter van Musschenbroek create at a namesake Dutch university in 1746 by lining a glass jar with silver foil?", "answer": "The Leyden jar", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff51638ff04d658268c92ee", "question": "What queen defeated and killed Cyrus the Great of Persia?", "answer": "Tomyris, a Massagetean ruler, led her armies against an attack by Cyrus the Great of the Achaemenid in 530 BC.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5909d1dfbb53d1af65886504", "question": "What American soul singer-songwriter died on December 25, 2006?", "answer": "James Brown", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cbf", "question": "Stores around the town square of Oxford, Mississippi closed during what author's 1962 funeral?", "answer": "William Faulkner", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398cc", "question": "Who played Tonto on the TV series \"The Lone Ranger\"?", "answer": "Jay Silverheels", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015f87dfe83fe1f2a824c2e", "question": "In which ancient South Asian language is the text of The Vedas written?", "answer": "Sanskrit - The religious poems originated in northwestern India in 1500-1000 BCE.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5c62b92b0ae4aacefc17eee3", "question": "Which team won the 2018 Major League Baseball World Series Title?", "answer": "Boston Red Sox", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b10f", "question": "At what Ohio university were four students shot to death during a 1970 anti-war demonstration?", "answer": "Kent State", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015e0d2fe83fe1f2a824b92", "question": "Against which country did the Soviet Union instigate an armed conflict in late 1939?", "answer": "Finland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59067a93ff9c0647b50a805b", "question": "What date did the United Kingdom European Union membership referendum took place on?", "answer": "June 23, 2016", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afe5", "question": "Who did George Bush Sr. defeat in the election in 1988?", "answer": "Michael Dukakis", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133917d", "question": "Who is the voice of Buzz Lightyear in the movie series Toy Story?", "answer": "Tim Allen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ade7", "question": "In 1944, who was the intended assassination victim of the July 20 Plot?", "answer": "Adolf Hitler", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391b0", "question": "Who played the role of Andy Dufresne in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "Tim Robbins", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c116", "question": "What year did Canadian figure skater, Elvis Stojko, retired from professional skating?", "answer": "2006", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396c7", "question": "What baseball team did Cheers' manager Sam Malone play for in the TV show?", "answer": "The Boston Red Sox", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aabb", "question": "In what modern-day country did the Sabines live?", "answer": "Italy", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe1f0a8145fb29466707390", "question": "What restaurant chain has commercials with the slogan \"Eatin' Good in the Neighborhood\"?", "answer": "Applebee's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff141a8b0ee8c595b6d39a5", "question": "Who wrote \"James and the Giant Peach\"?", "answer": "Roald Dahl", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a41e", "question": "What is the modern day equivalent of Formosa?", "answer": "Taiwan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb21", "question": "In 1990, what did the World Health Organization officially remove from its list of \"mental illnesses\"?", "answer": "Homosexuality", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015ff61fe83fe1f2a824c4e", "question": "In 1948, which NBA basketball team did the Harlem Globetrotters defeat which eventually helped break the NBA's color barrier?", "answer": "Minneapolis Lakers", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5feba92b7e83c707845b20d2", "question": "Sailors from years past suffered from scurvy due to a lack of what?", "answer": "Vitamin C", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cff", "question": "What category of writing are the Hugo Awards given for?", "answer": "Science-fiction", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c44d", "question": "How many chromosomes does an elephant have?", "answer": "56", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b569", "question": "What was the first Lifesaver flavor?", "answer": "Peppermint", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338983", "question": "Who is the tomboy main character in the book \"Little Women\"?", "answer": "Josephine (Jo) March", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fec86bcec223966ae8f8811", "question": "Who was the first female artist in history to have 4 consecutive singles from one album reach the Top 5 in the Billboard Hot 100?", "answer": "Cyndi Lauper's 1983 classic \"She's So Unusual\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393ed", "question": "What is the name of the funeral home in the TV show \"Six Feet Under\"?", "answer": "Fisher & Sons", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab2c", "question": "Suva is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Fiji", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c514", "question": "A hair that curls back on itself and penetrates the skin is known as what?", "answer": "Ingrown", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5904a4c7cf93664eb10486c6", "question": "Shortly after meeting David, which North American city did Katchoo disappear to for 2 months, in the comic series \"Strangers in Paradise\"?", "answer": "Toronto", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a58", "question": "What is the name of the actress who played Daphne on the TV show \"Frasier\"?", "answer": "Jane Leeves", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c966", "question": "If you are afraid of flying, what phobia do you have?", "answer": "Aviatophobia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "600cc2286de0eb824d4052e4", "question": "What U.S. state's official dessert is Smith Island Cake?", "answer": "Smith Island lies about 12 miles off the coast of Maryland in Chesapeake Bay and is home to the its tantalizing state dessert.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ae", "question": "What is the name of Johnny Depp's character in \"Pirates of the Caribbean\" movie franchise?", "answer": "Jack Sparrow", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c864", "question": "What pitcher lent his name to ulnar collateral ligament reconstruction?", "answer": "Tommy John", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58d1159a4fea7fe947a22268", "question": "Banjul is the capital of which African country?", "answer": "The Gambia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5c3e9a43ebfabb9c85d8a979", "question": "The meat pie, Tourtiere, originated in which country?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c55d", "question": "What are the four main ingredients of concrete?", "answer": "Sand, water, cement, gravel", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca62", "question": "The ore bauxite is the chief commercial source of which element?", "answer": "Aluminium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fc2", "question": "What jazz legend was named after his father, an East Saint Louis dentist who once ran for the Illinois state legislature?", "answer": "Miles Davis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a4a953661d1b4d384d5d676", "question": "Which dinosaur got its name because scientists thought that it fed on eggs?", "answer": "Oviraptor", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339832", "question": "The life of what jazz legend was portrayed in the 1988 film \"Bird\"?", "answer": "Charlie Parker", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60062ba7c9d816e292245c22", "question": "What is the name of Captain Ahab's ship?", "answer": "The Pequod", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339977", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", Lenny has a master's degree in what field?", "answer": "Nuclear Physics", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ab960586faa38a764be51a", "question": "What former republic did the Trabant originate from?", "answer": "East Germany, or German Democratic Republic", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d33", "question": "What surgeon on the TV show ER shares his name with a \"Warlord of Mars\" created by Edgar Rice Burroughs?", "answer": "John Carter", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af42", "question": "What was President John F. Kennedy's middle name?", "answer": "Fitzgerald", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bee2", "question": "Which US boxer was known as \"The Manessa Mauler\"?", "answer": "Jack Dempsey", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58b8d5412b42d4a3561a9f00", "question": "In the comic book series \"Strangers in Paradise\", what is the name of Francine\u2019s daughter?", "answer": "Jenny", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a642", "question": "What city is known as the \"Capital of the Silicon Valley\"?", "answer": "San Jose", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ae864e27f28483af1e7fdcf", "question": "In the 2016 film \"The Founder\" who plays Ray Kroc, who helped franchise McDonald\u2019s?", "answer": "Michael Keaton", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394bc", "question": "What is the name of Jack's pet parrot on the TV show \"Will & Grace\"?", "answer": "Guspo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c87c", "question": "What chemical element has an extra syllable in its more correct British pronunciation?", "answer": "Aluminium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339eb1", "question": "What screen legend made his final appearance in the movie \"The Thing Called Love\"?", "answer": "River Phoenix", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c85e", "question": "What does a hygrometer measure?", "answer": "Humidity", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b7d", "question": "Who is best known for his painting \"American Gothic\"?", "answer": "Grant Wood", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5bbd4c1c00d154d7af00b8cf", "question": "Who recorded the 1990's song \"Baby Got Back\"?", "answer": "Sir Mix-a-Lot", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a805", "question": "What is the name of the Canadian territory that shares a land border with Alaska?", "answer": "Yukon Territory", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58ab0fd0baab681b0929216a", "question": "Valentine's Day is also known as the \"Feast of...\" what?", "answer": "Saint Valentine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b663", "question": "Which automaker sold a car model named \"Colt\"?", "answer": "Dodge", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bacd", "question": "Who was the number 1 \u00adranked female tennis player in the world 7 out of 9 years between 1988 and 1996?", "answer": "Steffi Graf", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a862", "question": "The popular tourist destination, Amalfi, is located in which Italian region?", "answer": "Campania", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cc8", "question": "In a symphony orchestra, what instrument is played by the \"concertmaster\"?", "answer": "First violin", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe69a4c20565ad31a57c752", "question": "Plato thought the Lost Island of Atlantis was linked to which ancient culture?", "answer": "Minoan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a533", "question": "The Missouri River flows into what river?", "answer": "Mississippi River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe7bf34877e98cb97778966", "question": "Lake Titicaca sits on the border between what two nations?", "answer": "Bolivia and Peru", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aef1", "question": "When did The Black Death reach London?", "answer": "1348", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5b358e1d5db0d66a186cb566", "question": "During the 1990\u2019s who recorded the albums \"Out of Time\" and \"New Adventures in Hi-Fi\"?", "answer": "R.E.M.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a88", "question": "Which comic strip character is the owner of a dog named Otto?", "answer": "Sgt. Snorkel", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5be5812d5415ba52ed6f0abe", "question": "What year did H. G. Well publish the comic novel \"The History of Mr Polly\"?", "answer": "1910", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "601b48b749076251badbeaa5", "question": "Who was the oldest person to travel in space?", "answer": "John Glenn -- He was 77-years-old when he returned to space on the Space Shuttle Discovery's STS-95 mission.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a699", "question": "What are the 4 US state capitols and states that begin with the same letter?", "answer": "Dover Delaware, Honolulu Hawaii, Indianapolis Indiana, Oklahoma City, Oklahoma", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d83", "question": "Whose posthumous albums include \"R U Still Down?\", \"Still I Rise\", and \"Until the End of Time\"?", "answer": "Tupac Shakur", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aeb7", "question": "Which American statistician founded the institute of Public Opinion in 1935?", "answer": "Gallup", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff515beff04d658268c92ec", "question": "What queen led a famous revolt against the Roman Empire?", "answer": "Zenobia, queen of the Palmyrene Empire, expanded the empire, by conquering Egypt and expelling the Roman prefect, Tenagino Probus.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1df", "question": "In the restaurant world, what does \"Blue-plate special\" refer to?", "answer": "Low-priced specials that change daily", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a929", "question": "Where is the Boxing Hall of Fame located?", "answer": "Canastota, New York", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe4ef0a06d333868d34d777", "question": "What is primarily used to make traditional hummus?", "answer": "Chickpeas", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4cc", "question": "What US state capital took its name from the French for \"red stick\"?", "answer": "Baton Rouge", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfea", "question": "Is kissing under the mistletoe comes from whose customs?", "answer": "Druids", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7fd", "question": "In what layer of the Earth's atmosphere is Antarctica's famed \"ozone hole\"?", "answer": "Stratosphere", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58b8cc2f94b094db9158309d", "question": "Who was the first person to receive an \"Honorary Award\" at the Academy Awards?", "answer": "Charlie Chaplin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b765", "question": "The soft drink Mr. Pibb was introduced as a competitor to which popular soft drink?", "answer": "Dr. Pepper", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe12f35e39efa6330e0fed7", "question": "Where is the world's shortest commercial runway?", "answer": "Saba", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a6f", "question": "Who played Willy Wonka in the original version of \"Willy Wonka and the Chocolate Factory\"?", "answer": "Gene Wilder", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfd0", "question": "What is the NATO phonetic alphabet word for \"E\"?", "answer": "Echo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b430", "question": "What year did Alfred Hitchcock die?", "answer": "1980", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392ee", "question": "In the 1988 movie \"Die Hard\", what does John McClane leave in the limo?", "answer": "A teddy bear", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae6d", "question": "What did the class entering Harvard in the fall of 1967 have for the first time?", "answer": "Women", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fede4316ce05a3942286dd9", "question": "Parts of the movie \"Lara Croft: Tomb Raider\" were shot in what African country?", "answer": "Kenya", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b6c", "question": "What Hanna-Barbera cartoon character was known for the catchphrase \"Exit, Stage Left\" when dashing off?", "answer": "Snagglepuss", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cf4", "question": "Where did the Gilmore Girls reside?", "answer": "Stars Hollow", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a444", "question": "Which river separates Mexico from the US?", "answer": "Rio Grande", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a55a", "question": "What is the capital of Alaska?", "answer": "Juneau", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a818", "question": "After Central Park was completed, New York City's 4th Avenue, above 32nd Street, was renamed what?", "answer": "Park Avenue", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a701", "question": "Which US state is home to the Inyo Mountains?", "answer": "California", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5af25bccb63e5727cf5a485c", "question": "Who did Luther Vandross duet with in the 1992 single \"Best Things In Life Are Free\"?", "answer": "Janet Jackson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6d2", "question": "What disease was once nicknamed \"the white plague\"?", "answer": "Tuberculosis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339866", "question": "In Disney's \"Pinocchio\", what is the name of Geppetto's cat?", "answer": "Figaro", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b63f", "question": "What spice comes from the herb called cilantro?", "answer": "Coriander", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe733d9eec85e375820b226", "question": "What was the code name for the Battle of Okinawa?", "answer": "Operation Iceberg", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b6e", "question": "What classic science-fiction movie features a giant robot named Gort?", "answer": "The Day the Earth Stood Still", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339818", "question": "What are the names of the five Planeteers from the TV show \"Captain Planet and The Planeteers\"?", "answer": "Kwame, Wheeler, Linka, Gi, and Ma-Ti", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd968de23c87fd04dd15e05", "question": "What did the BBC broadcast on the \"day without news\" in 1930?", "answer": "Piano music", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c83a", "question": "What irrational number is the base of a natural logarithm?", "answer": "e", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3ac", "question": "What writing system originated in Sumer around 3,000 BCE?", "answer": "Cuneiform", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f35", "question": "Who titled his 1989 autobiography \"Holy Cow!\"?", "answer": "Harry Caray", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb55", "question": "Who was the first African-American player inducted into the Baseball Hall of Fame?", "answer": "Jackie Robinson", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b77c", "question": "According to legend, the \"Witch of November\" had a hand in the fate of what ship?", "answer": "Edmund Fitzgerald", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600242794be4723ccac22186", "question": "Atticus Finch is the name of the narrator\u2019s father in which classic 1960 novel?", "answer": "\"To Kill a Mockingbird\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe734a7eec85e375820b23a", "question": "How did General Erwin Rommel die?", "answer": "Suicide", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c30b", "question": "How fast can bees fly?", "answer": "15 miles per hour", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59db76d20ab2c8f322317fe7", "question": "In which ocean or sea are the Seychelles?", "answer": "Indian Ocean", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4b3", "question": "Sharpshooter Phoebe Ann Mosey was better known as who?", "answer": "Annie Oakley", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600cc6d76de0eb824d4052f9", "question": "Where is the world\u2019s largest living tree canopy, the size of three soccer fields?", "answer": "India -- A 550-year-old ficus benghalensis tree there, known as Thimmamma Marrimanu, has combined crowns that span 5.41 acres.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be08", "question": "Which of Santa's reindeer have names that mean \"thunder\" and \"lightning\" in German?", "answer": "Donner and Blitzen", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c77d", "question": "What precious stones were originally used to polish axes in the Stone Age?", "answer": "Diamonds", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a6", "question": "What movie starred Mel Gibson as William Wallace?", "answer": "Braveheart", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a76e", "question": "The Gaza Strip extends northeast from what peninsula?", "answer": "Sinai Peninsula", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ac3", "question": "Joe Cool is an alter ego of which comic strip character?", "answer": "Snoopy", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5902a1a5cad1ec93f27df778", "question": "In English-speaking countries, what is Rauchbier typically referred to as?", "answer": "Smoked beer", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a01c", "question": "What actor was the narrator in the movie \"The Texas Chain Saw Massacre\"?", "answer": "John Larroquette", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c49f", "question": "Decompression sickness, which can occur when a diver surfaces too quickly is also called what?", "answer": "The bends", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fea3d00ff048f679a45ab45", "question": "What is a body's resistance to changes in motion or speed called?", "answer": "Inertia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d52", "question": "What Herman Melville character always answers \"I would prefer not to\" whenever his boss asks him to work?", "answer": "Bartleby the Scrivener", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c865", "question": "What German mathematician devised an impossible one-sided bottle?", "answer": "Felix Klein", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0e6", "question": "On what date did the Menendez murders take place?", "answer": "August 20, 1989", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339679", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is the name of Homer's half brother?", "answer": "Herb", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8f33d01dd7bf43be5e816", "question": "In the US, what does AARP stand for?", "answer": "American Association of Retired Persons", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339469", "question": "Who drinks Tim's lava lamp in the 1999 movie \"My Favourite Martian\"?", "answer": "Martin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bac2", "question": "What do the letters YMCA stand for?", "answer": "Young Men\u2019s Christian Association", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339682", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is the name of the frozen drink sold at the Kwik-E-Mart?", "answer": "Squishee", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a025", "question": "What is the name of the female field reporter for Channel 5 News in the TV show \"Family Guy\"?", "answer": "Tricia Takanawa", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339396", "question": "Who directed the 1999 movie \"Bowfinger\"?", "answer": "Frank Oz", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bce", "question": "Which pair of German brothers collected such stories as \"Hansel & Gretel\"?", "answer": "The Brothers Grimm", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339506", "question": "What does Lilo give Stitch to drink in a baby bottle?", "answer": "Coffee", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c57", "question": "How many years were Whitney Houston and Bobby Brown married for?", "answer": "15", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339640", "question": "Oswald Cobblepot is better known as who?", "answer": "The Penguin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "592ead58f83302ff91e4647a", "question": "Sophophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Learning", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5e7", "question": "Bill Cosby is a famous alumnus of what Philadelphia university?", "answer": "Temple University", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e7f", "question": "During what war was the novel \"Simplicissimus\" set?", "answer": "Thirty Years' War", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c53d", "question": "Where in your body is your patella?", "answer": "The knee", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb05", "question": "Along with Indiana Ave, and Illinois Ave, what is the third third red property on a Monopoly board?", "answer": "Kentucky Ave.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c76c", "question": "What explorer introduced chickens to the New World?", "answer": "Christopher Columbus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b764", "question": "The name \"Chandler\" literally means what?", "answer": "Candlemaker", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c221", "question": "What is the name of Canada's national anthem?", "answer": "O Canada", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c93d", "question": "What bird is the smallest living bird?", "answer": "Bee Hummingbird", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a043", "question": "John Oliver began hosting what show for HBO in 2014?", "answer": "Last Week Tonight", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338895", "question": "What has no reflection, no shadow and cannot stand the smell of garlic?", "answer": "A vampire", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a45b", "question": "Where is the Pentagon building physically located?", "answer": "Arlington, Virginia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5febd4bc7e83c707845b215f", "question": "During which period in Japanese history did \"Seven Samurai\" take place?", "answer": "Sengoku Period", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cad7", "question": "Hydrargyrum is an old name for which element on the periodic table?", "answer": "Mercury", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b697", "question": "What is a \"major-domo\"?", "answer": "A chief steward", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b56a", "question": "Which automaker opened the first foreign plant in the US?", "answer": "Volkswagen", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133940b", "question": "What is the name of Drew Barrymore's character in the 1982 movie E.T. the Extra Terrestrial\"?", "answer": "Gertie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdb3", "question": "What Big US East school took the cryptic name for its sports teams from the Greek word for \"what\"?", "answer": "Georgetown", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5990af23b72eedf883a8c704", "question": "What is Chopin's \"Piano Sonata in B flat minor\" also known as?", "answer": "The Funeral March", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133898d", "question": "What name did the meaner of Cinderella's stepsisters call her?", "answer": "Cinderwench", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3e5", "question": "Billy The Kid, during the Lincoln County War, joined a gang known as the what?", "answer": "Regulators", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea41d8ff048f679a45ab72", "question": "Which breed did the English call a coach dog", "answer": "Dalmatian", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6c1", "question": "What is the capital of Kansas?", "answer": "Topeka", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe9f0bdff048f679a45aaa5", "question": "Tachophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Speed", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b87c", "question": "Sinologists study what?", "answer": "China and Chinese topics", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b08d", "question": "The British passed the Intolerable Acts as punishment for what act by the American colonists?", "answer": "The Boston Tea Party", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133908f", "question": "Who is the Roman equivalent of the Greek goddess Eirene?", "answer": "Pax", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58d077c9870e6f05ba600867", "question": "What film starred Drew Barrymore, Mary-Louise Parker, and Matthew McConaughey?", "answer": "Boys on the Side", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bab6", "question": "What is the first name of the drummer for the band Van Halen?", "answer": "Alex", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffb61365dad637d903c882e", "question": "What is the smallest country in South America?", "answer": "Suriname", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58dba546874c93a3298b214f", "question": "What is the name of Princess Anne's second husband", "answer": "Timothy Laurence", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffb69b55dad637d903c8849", "question": "Which university\u2019s mascot is the same as its state\u2019s animal?", "answer": "Wisconsin", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe938d96bd93ce3a4e5f688", "question": "What branch of science is concerned with the interaction between matter and electromagnetic radiation?", "answer": "Spectroscopy", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6002436e4be4723ccac22196", "question": "In Jonathan Swift\u2019s \"Gulliver\u2019s Travels\", what is the name of the island inhabited by tiny people?", "answer": "Lilliput", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3c2", "question": "How many U.S. states are there?", "answer": "Fifty", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aab2", "question": "Which bird is the national bird of Belarus?", "answer": "White stork", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1ef", "question": "What is added to cachaca to make a Caipirinha?", "answer": "Sugar and lime", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c03a", "question": "Where is the Popliteal Fossa located?", "answer": "Back of the knee", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff517fcff04d658268c92fe", "question": "By which nickname is Henry McCarty better known?", "answer": "Billy the Kid", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6014c64ffbde8045e48466b5", "question": "The asteroid that killed the dinosaurs is believed to have landed where?", "answer": "About 65 million years ago, an asteroid about 6 miles wide crashed into the Gulf of Mexico, killing 70% of all species on Earth.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fedda276ce05a3942286d82", "question": "What is the first thing Andy seeks to get in prison in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "Andy asks Red to get him a rock hammer.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396b9", "question": "What candy does E.T. love?", "answer": "Reese's Pieces", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133930f", "question": "In \"The Big Lebowski\", what did Jeffrey Lebowski want replaced after it was urinated on?", "answer": "His rug", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6a7cf20565ad31a57c7ef", "question": "What was the first US state to pass a law requiring mandatory seat belt use?", "answer": "New York", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f7c", "question": "In Greek mythology, what did the cyclops forge for Zeus?", "answer": "Thunderbolts", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acb4", "question": "How many days were there in the ancient Egyptian year?", "answer": "365", "category": "history"}, {"id": "60078be90eee65b76b9f266e", "question": "In which country did the first World War I battle take place?", "answer": "Belgium (The first official battle of WWI occurred at the city named Liege. The city was taken by Germany by August 15, 1914.)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd66230a5bfecdd737e0842", "question": "How many planets in our solar system have rings?", "answer": "4", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b473", "question": "What duo first published the \"Michelin Guide\" in 1900?", "answer": "Andre and Edouard Michelin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bad3", "question": "An English fire hydrant is said to be the inspiration behind the unique bottle of what liquor brand?", "answer": "Tanqueray", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8ee", "question": "Which letter stands for the Roman number 50?", "answer": "L", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a36b", "question": "What country administers Greenland?", "answer": "Denmark", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392b8", "question": "Who directed the 1980 movie \"The Blues Brothers\"?", "answer": "John Landis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a45", "question": "According to Greek mythology, what was the only spirit that remained in Pandora's box?", "answer": "Hope", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c863", "question": "What 's the largest bird in North America?", "answer": "California condor", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd82", "question": "What type of animal is the Japanese monster, Ebirah?", "answer": "Shrimp", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a31d", "question": "John Travolta, Samuel Jackson, Uma Thurman starred in which 1994 Quentin Tarantino film?", "answer": "Pulp Fiction", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0a6", "question": "What was the name of the restaurant the TV series \"Happy Days\"?", "answer": "Arnolds", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff51274ff04d658268c92d0", "question": "What was the most popular drink in colonial America?", "answer": "Nearly everyone in colonial America drank\u00a0tea, which explains the uproar when the British levied a tax on their favorite drink.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbab", "question": "What game introduced the characters Raiden, Liu Kang, and Sub-Zero?", "answer": "Mortal Kombat", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339916", "question": "What was the name of Vince Vaughn\u2019s gymnasium in \u201cDodgeball: A True Underdog Story\u201d?", "answer": "Average Joe's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c611", "question": "On a map, the horizontal lines are called what?", "answer": "Latitude", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c243", "question": "How many sides does a decagon have?", "answer": "Ten", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c20b", "question": "Why were the 1916 Olympic Games cancelled?", "answer": "Due to World War I", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c0c", "question": "What year was Barbra Streisand born in?", "answer": "1942", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58f5649133a95c66dc4fe74f", "question": "Roman Polanski directed which 1974 film starring Jack Nicholson?", "answer": "Chinatown", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5e5f0fc7d274615ecf514536", "question": "Which plant has the most genes of any living plant or animal?", "answer": "Paris Japonica", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe1eca1145fb29466707387", "question": "What does the Qantas airline name stand for?", "answer": "Queensland and Northern Territory Aerial Services", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015f757fe83fe1f2a824c20", "question": "Which U.S. President worked as a tailor and made his own suits?", "answer": "Before he became President, Andrew Johnson worked as a tailor in Greeneville, Tennessee.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be31", "question": "How many players are there in a standard beach volleyball team?", "answer": "Two", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c48", "question": "What year did fashion designer Alexander McQueen commit suicide?", "answer": "2010", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b86a", "question": "What is the Syrah grape called in Australia?", "answer": "Shiraz", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa9a", "question": "How many stars does the New Zealand national flag have?", "answer": "Four", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389b6", "question": "Whose still-life painting, \"Rideau Cruchon et Compotier\", sold for $60.5 million in 1999?", "answer": "Paul Cezanne's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8f1", "question": "A Phon is a unit of what?", "answer": "Loudness", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d0a", "question": "What movie's first sequel featured the subtitle \"The Edge of Reason\"?", "answer": "Bridget Jones's Diary", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff51959ff04d658268c9301", "question": "What year did Christmas become a statutory holiday in Iraq?", "answer": "In December 2008, the Iraqi cabinet made December 25, Christmas Day, an official holiday throughout the entire country.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad83", "question": "Who sent the Spanish Armada to invade England?", "answer": "Philip II", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fefbee06ce05a3942286ef8", "question": "Who recorded the song \"King for a Day\"?", "answer": "Thompson Twins", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339535", "question": "Who played Lois in \"Lois & Clark: The New Adventures of Superman\"?", "answer": "Teri Hatcher", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339930", "question": "Who directed the Michael Jackson music videos for \"Thriller\" and \"Black and White\"?", "answer": "John Landis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe1f378145fb2946670739a", "question": "What cheese is traditionally used on a Reuben sandwich?", "answer": "Swiss", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c403", "question": "What color is soapstone when it is first mined?", "answer": "Blue", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5febd47d7e83c707845b215d", "question": "Who is the world-famous writer and director of \"Seven Samurai\"?", "answer": "Akira Kurosawa", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600780f8bd51d85e222ab646", "question": "What is the main visual element in Impressionist painting?", "answer": "They were interested in trying to capture the changing effects of light by using a more exact analysis of tone and color.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5febd7137e83c707845b2171", "question": "Which character in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\" bets Andy would be the first to crack on his first night in the prison?", "answer": "Red", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59049d99cf93664eb10486af", "question": "The plane carrying what country\u2019s national rugby team crashed on Friday, October 13, 1972?", "answer": "Uruguay\u2019s", "category": "general"}, {"id": "592eaff9f83302ff91e46497", "question": "Jimmy Connors won the men's doubles at the 1973 Wimbledon with which partner?", "answer": "Ilie Nastase", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8e7", "question": "What does a pedometer count?", "answer": "Steps", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5990b018b72eedf883a8c70f", "question": "In what country do people speak the language they call Nihongo?", "answer": "Japan", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe0da77fcbed638185eaa04", "question": "Which city has the world\u2019s largest network of aerial cable cars?", "answer": "La Paz, Bolivia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd37", "question": "Who scored the famous \"Hand of God\" goal in the 1986 World Cup?", "answer": "Diego Maradona", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7c3e1877e98cb97778998", "question": "What is the lowest elevation river in the world?", "answer": "Jordan River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c6b", "question": "The 1977 movie \"Saturday Night Fever\" was based on what \"New York\" magazine article?", "answer": "Tribal Rites of the New Saturday Night", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe65e661f3c0ead6880d62c", "question": "In the Bible, who was considered the Weeping Prophet?", "answer": "Jeremiah", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59ae94fc574a5ce6b56b824e", "question": "Lilongwe is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Malawi", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a162cc3f01ec323f8491732", "question": "Arnold Schwarzenegger played Douglas Quaid in which 1990 film?", "answer": "Total Recall", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015eaf2fe83fe1f2a824bf6", "question": "Which Native American tribe took part in the first Thanksgiving feast?", "answer": "Wampanoag", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5a3", "question": "Who was the 1994 Fifa World Cup winner?", "answer": "Brazil", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a844", "question": "What UK city is served by John Lennon Airport?", "answer": "Liverpool", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a263", "question": "Alanis Morrisette appeared on what 1980's TV show?\u00a0", "answer": "You Can't Do that On Television", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394ea", "question": "What TV show began with the words \"There is nothing wrong with your television set.\"?", "answer": "The Outer Limits", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe65cb41f3c0ead6880d617", "question": "In what country did the concept of Easter bunny originate?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aaf0", "question": "What is the capital of the US state Wisconsin?", "answer": "Madison", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd81dced0de9af39e9d4693", "question": "What state elected a former pro wrestler as its governor?", "answer": "Minnesota", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c754", "question": "What layer of the atmosphere is closest to the earth?", "answer": "The Troposphere", "category": "science"}]